Sub-zero heroes.
Ice Age is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Chris Wedge.
Manny the mammoth, Sid the loquacious sloth, and Diego the sabre-toothed tiger go on a comical quest
to return a human baby back to his father, across a world on the brink of an ice age.
Manny (voice), played by Ray Romano.
Sid (voice), played by John Leguizamo.
Diego (voice), played by Denis Leary.
Soto (voice), played by Goran Višnjić.
Zeke (voice), played by Jack Black.
Carl (voice), played by Cedric the Entertainer.
Ice Age is a 2002 American animated adventure comedy film directed by
Chris Wedge and written by Michael Berg, Michael J.
Wilson, and Peter Ackerman.
Produced by Blue Sky Studios as its first feature film, it features an ensemble voice
cast, including Ray Romano, John Leguizamo, Denis Leary and Jack Black.
Set during the days of the Pleistocene ice age, the film centers around Manny, a no-nonsense woolly mammoth, Sid, a loudmouthed
ground sloth, and Diego, a sardonic smilodon, who come across a human baby and work together to return it to its tribe.
Ice Age was originally conceived by Fox Animation Studios as a traditionally animated film, but became a full-length CGI
film from Blue Sky, which had been transformed from a visual effects house to a computer animation studio.
Focus shifted from making an action-adventure drama film to a more comedy-oriented one, and
several writers, including Berg and Ackerman, were brought on to lighten the tone.
David Newman composed and conducted the film's musical score.
Ice Age was released in the United States on March 15, 2002 by 20th Century Fox.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and was a box office success, grossing $383 million,
and becoming the eighth highest-grossing film and the highest-grossing animated film of 2002.
It was nominated at the 75th Academy Awards for Best Animated Feature.
It spawned a franchise, consisting of several sequels,
spin-offs, specials, shorts, and video games.
The film explores themes of dying and death, human evolution,
parent child relationship, squirrel, loss of loved one.
The tone is lighthearted.